Literatura de Cordel collection, 1918-1995
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Pelejas (Poetic Contests)., 1918-1995.
  - Title: Peleja de Zé Felix com Mangabeira Author: unknown Illustrator: signed Stênio Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 29/11/74. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: 2a peleja de José Pontual com Vicente Emiliano Author: José Pontual Illustrator: signed J.B. Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, PE Other: acrostic, JOZEP.PONTUAL., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: A peleja dos Ipixunas com os brancos invasores Author: Jairo Mozart Illustrator: signed J.MIGUEL Publisher: Fundação Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, PE Other: acrostic, JOZEP.PONTUAL., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino da Silva com Cicero Bandeira de Melo Author: José Severino da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Patativa com Ana Rouxinha Author: José Jeronymo Pereira Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, PEREIRA., 20/1/52. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de José Nilton de Oliveira com José Pedro Pontual Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Nilton de Oliveira (Alejadinho) Other: acrostic, PONTUAL., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Ferreirinha com Apolônio Alves dos Santos Author: Manoel Ferreira Sobrinho (Ferreirinha) Illustrator: signed J.BARROS Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb.., after 1978. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Xudú com Azulão Authors: Manoel Xudú Sobrinho, José João dos Santos (Azulão) Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, AZULAO., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Xudú Sobrinho e Zezé Lulu Author: Manoel Xudú Publisher: Relojoaria São Francisco Place: João Pessoa, Paraiba., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Borges com João Barraca Author: Severino Borges da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Milanês com Severino Pinto Author: Severino Milanês da Silva Illustrator: signed Stênio Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda.., 8/9/77. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja do Cego Aderaldo com Zé Pretinho Author: Firmino Teixeira do Amaral Illustrator: signed Stênio Publisher: Lira Nordestina Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 28/12/81. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Marcolino Cobra Verde com Laurindo Gato Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: A Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 3/8/56. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Riachão com o Diabo Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: unknown Place: Recife, Pernambuco., 28 de maio de 1937. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de João Athayde com o Leandro Gomes Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 24/6/56. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de João Severo de Lima com Manoel Camilo dos Santos Author: João Severo de Lima Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Place: Campina Grande., 30/11/77. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de João Severo de Lima com Lino Pedro Azul Author: João Severo de Lima Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Livraria e Tipografia NABUCO Place: Patos, Pb., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de José Pontul com José Herminio Author: José Herminio Illustrator: signed J.B. Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Concluintes 1983 Curso Jornalismo Universidade Católica de Pernambuco Author: Delarme Monteiro Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco Other: acrostic, DELARME. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Cachimbinho e Geraldo Mousinho cantando suas emboladas Authors: Cachimbinho, Geraldo Mousinho Publisher: Antonio da Mulatinha Place: Campina Grande., 25/1/1977. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de Dedé Redeiro com o Índio do Amazonas Author: Dedé Redeiro Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Paraíba., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de José de Sousa Campos com Severino Milanez da Silva Author: José de Sousa Campos Publisher: Tip. d'A Folha Place: Tabaiana, PB., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Grande desafio dos repentistas Heleno Severino e José Severino Cristóvão Authors: José S. Cristóvão, Heleno Severino Illustrator: signed VALÉRIO Publisher: J. S. Cristóvão Place: Caruaru, PE., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Grande desafio dos repentistas Heleno Severino e José Severino Cristóvão Authors: José S. Cristóvão, Heleno Severino Illustrator: signed DILLA Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: A grande peleja de Ivanildo Vila Nova com Manoel Camilo dos Santos Authors: Ivanildo Vila Nova Publisher: Biblioteca da Vida Rural Brasileira, MEC/PRONOSEC RURAL SEC/Pb UFPb FUNAPE Other: acrostic, MANOEL CAMILO., 1981. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Title: Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia Author: unknown Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, GUSTAVO., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Otília Soares com Manoel Francisco Duda Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Folhetaria São José Place: Condado, Pe Other: acrostic, J.COSTA., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Grande desafio do Poeta Walério com o escritor José Severino Cristóvão (pai e filho) Author: Walério, José Severino Cristóvão Illustrator: signed VALÉRIO Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de João Athayde com Leandro Gomes de Barros Author: unknown Publisher: Tip São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Riachão com o Diabo Author: João Martins de Athayde Publisher: Casa Athayde Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 3/3/50. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Discussão de Vida-Torta com Chica Pendão Author: Guriatã do Norte Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: O grande desafio de J.Borges com João Vicente Emiliano Author: João Vicente Emiliano Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia Author: José Gustavo Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará Other: acrostic, GUSTAVO., 20/12/56. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia Author: José Gustavo Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda. Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará Other: acrostic, GUSTAVO., 2/7/1977. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia Author: José Gustavo Publisher: Lira Nordestina Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará Other: acrostic, GUSTAVO., 20/01/82. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de José Gustavo com Maria Rouxinha da Bahia Author: José Gustavo Publisher: Tip. São Francisco Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará Other: acrostic, GUSTAVO., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Raimundo com Manoel Campinas Author: unknown Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 23/5/57. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Riachão com o Diabo Author: João Martins de Athayde Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: José Bernardo da Silva Ltda. Place: Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará., 29/1/1978. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Manoel Riachão Sobrinho com José Maneiro Author: José Pacheco Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Grande debate de José Soares com Bernardino de Sena sobre o divórcio Author: Bernardino de Sena Illustrator: signed JERONIMO Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Grande peleja de José Cristóvão com wandeleide Cristóvão Author: Bernardino de Sena Illustrator: signed VALÉRIO Publisher: unknown., ca. 1977. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: O grande peleja de Severino Borges com Severino Ciríaco Author: unknown Publisher: João José Silva., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Natanael de Lima com Apolônio Alves dos Santos Author: Natanael de Lima Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb. Other: acrostic, NDELIMA., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: A esmagadora peleja de João Vicente Emiliano com José Pedro Pontual Author: José Pedro Pontual Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Zé Pretinho com Maria Roxinha da Bahia Author: José Costa Leite Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, J.COSTA., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Um desafio original Author: Ernesto Vêra Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Typographia Guajarina Place: Belem, Pará., 1932. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Desafio dos glosadores Gerson Lucena com Antonio da Mulatinha Author: Gerson Lucena Illustrator: signed LUCENA Publisher: Joaquim Duarte Place: Campina Grande, Paraíba Other: acrostic, GERSON LUCENA., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Grande peleja de Olegário com Antonio Gavião Author: Olegário Fernandes da Silva Illustrator: signed NILSON Publisher: Folheteria Boa Vista Place: Caruaru, Pernambuco Other: acrostic, OLEGARIO., after 1940. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Pinto com Milanês Author: Severino Milanês da Silva Illustrator: signed STÊNIO Publisher: Lira Nordestina Place: Juazeiro, Ceará., 02/01/82. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Borges com Patativa do Norte Author: Severino Borges da Silva Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: João José da Silva Place: Recife, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Borges com Tindara Author: Severino Borges da Silva Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: S. B. da Silva Place: Timbaúba, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Borges com Severino Pereira Author: Severino Borges da Silva Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Milanez e Manoel Clemente Author: Severino Cesário Publisher: Universidade Federal de Pernambuco Other: acrostic, SEVERINO CESARIO., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Borges com Mocinha do Pará Author: Severino Borges Illustrator: signed JOTABARROS Publisher: Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Simeão com Ana Roxinha Author: Severino Simeão Illustrator: signed J.MIGUEL Publisher: unknown., 1930. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Simeão com Ana Roxinha Author: Severino Simeão Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1940. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Severino Carlos com Manoel Apolinario em quadrão a beira-mar Author: Severino Carlos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, S.CARLOS., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: Peleja de Ló e Léu pela a Dorinha Duval Author: Nilton José da Silva Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Title: A deferente peleja do Crioulo Doido com Coronel Ludugero Author: Franklin Machado Nordestino Illustrator: signed MAXADO Publisher: F. M. Nordestino Place: São Paulo Other: acrostic, MAXADO., 1976. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja do artesão Author: João Francisco da Silva Publisher: Alternativa Gráfica Place: Recife, PE Other: acrostic, JOAOFS., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Ismael Garcia com o Negro Lavareda Author: Expedito F. Silva Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: E. F. Silva., 16/10/89. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de João Coletto com o Diabo Author: Geraldo Peres Generoso Illustrator: Cicero de Pais Publisher: unknown., 1989. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Chicotingole com Chica Esporão Author: Heleno Francisco Torres Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: O baiano está feliz com a volta do mercado Author: Antônio Ribeiro da Conceição (Bule-Bule) Publisher: unknown., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: O encontro de João Ramos com Severino Severo Author: João Crispim Ramos Publisher: Artes Grafoca Vitória Ltda. Place: Feira de Santana, Bahia., 1984. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: O encontro de João Ramos com Zezinho da Bahia Author: João Crispim Ramos Publisher: Artes Grafoca Vitória Ltda. Place: Feira de Santana, Bahia., 1984. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Encontro de Lampião com Zé Guará um valente cangaceiro do E. da Bahia Author: Severino Cesário da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown Place: Recife, Pernambuco., 1980. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Nao pode faltar repente na boca do cantador (mote) Author: Otavio de Menezes Illustrator: Ronaldo Cavalcante Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelistas do Ceará (CECORDEL) Place: Fortaleza, Ceará., 17/12/88. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Palestra Author: Elias A. de Carvalho Publisher: E. A de Carvalho Place: Petrópolis, RJ Other: acrostic, CARVALHO., 1984. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Zé Sarney com Ulisses Guimarães Author: Manoel Santa Maria Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO 88 Publisher: unknown., 1988. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Poetas ganham moção de louvor da câmara municipal e certificado da ARCOB Author: Expedito F. Silva Illustrator: signed ERIVALDO Publisher: unknown., 1988. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: A peleja do povo contra o homem que quer cercar o mundo Author: Sabiá da Mata Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Gráfica Casa das Crianças de Olinda Place: Olinda, Pernambuco., 1979. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja das diretas o desafio do ano com José Moacir e Zé Golvêia Author: José Moacir de Sousa Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Cantando Goiás e os seus valores Author: José Moacir de Sousa Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante., 1986. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Um repentista cantando a natureza Author: Luiz Nava Illustrator: signed JRS Publisher: L. Nava Place: Goiânia, Goiás., 1986. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Encontro de Luiz Nava com Mercides Nonato Author: Luiz Nava Illustrator: signed DILA Publisher: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Filho Place: Goiânia, Goiás., 1988. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Encontro de Miguel Martins com Dico Nava no céu Author: Luiz Nava Publisher: Rodolfo Coelho Cavalcante Filho Place: Goiânia, Goiás., 1988. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: A reabertura da banca dos trovadores e repentistas na praça do mercado modelo Author: Antonio Brito de Souza Illustrator: Jussandir Raimundo de Souza signed JRS Publisher: unknown., 1985. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Azulão vem aí! Para Vereador José João dos Santos Author: José João dos Santos (Azulão) Publisher: unknown Other: acrostic, AZULAO., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: A peleja entre o pureza e o fumaça Author: Geraldo Carvalho (PARDAL) Publisher: Centro Cultural dos Cordelista do Ceará., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: A grande peleja de Preto Limão com Inacio da Catingueira Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: A. A. dos Santos Place: Rio de Janeiro, RJ., janeiro de 1987. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Bule-Bule com Valdomiro Galvão Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb Other: acrostic, AALVES., 1978. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Zé Limeira com Severino Tempero Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed JCL Publisher: Tip. Pontes Place: Guarabira, Pb Other: acrostic, AALVES., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Discussão de José Ventura com Apolônio Alves dos Santos Author: Apolônio Alves dos Santos Illustrator: signed Ciro Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: A malassombrada peleja de Francisco Sales com o Negro Visão Author: Francisco Sales Arêda Illustrator: unsigned Publisher: João José da Silva Other: acrostic, FSALES., 1900s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Maxado Nordestino com o Raimundo Santa Helena neste rio Author: João Paraíba Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Oscar Alho e Francisco Malagueta Author: Gonçalo Ferreira da Silva Illustrator: signed MS Publisher: unknown., after 1950. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Pinto com Milanês Author: Severino Milanês da Silva Illustrator: signed J.BORGES Publisher: unknown., after 1940. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Title: Peleja de Dimas e Otacílio Batista, O valor que o chifre tem Author: Dimas e Otacílio Batista Publisher: unknown Place: João Pessoa., 1975. (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Original woodblock print., undated. (Box 24, Folder 6)